Guide to the Council of Latin American Studies, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Council of Latin American Studies, Yale University, records
1965-1970
RU 945
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, subject files, maintained by Chairman Richard McGee Morse, documenting the Yale Council on Latin American Studies. A vita of Richard M. Morse is included.
Yale Center for International and Area Studies. Council on Latin American Studies
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, subject files, maintained by Chairman Richard McGee Morse, documenting the Yale Council on Latin American Studies. A vita of Richard M. Morse is included.
Latin America -- Study and teaching; Research institutes; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Morse, Richard M. (Richard McGee), 1922-2001; Yale Center for International and Area Studies. Council on African Studies; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students
- Records of Richard Morse as Chairman, circa 1967-1971; Accession 2004-A-083
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are partially restricted.
  Restrictions are noted at the folder level
  - Recommendations--Students, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2046
  - Brasilia, University of, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - City College, City University of New York, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Columbia University, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cornell University, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Latin American Studies Programs:Harvard-Columbia-etc., 1961-1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Berkeley, University of California, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - State University of New York, Stony Brook, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Recommendations, 1952-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scholar-of-the-House Program, 1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Senior Appointment Committee in the Social Sciences, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Spanish Department, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Requests for Reprinting, 1967, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Recommendations External Faculty, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Recommendations Internal Faculty, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2045
  - Publishers: Scott Foresman and Co. (Latin American Series), 1967, 1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Request for Publications and Reviews, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Publishers--Correspondence, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Text Book Department, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Black Heritage - David Walker, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Vita - Morse, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Undergraduates Papers, Grades, General, 1968, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2048
  - Departmental Negotiations--Faculty, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - SAB--Student Advisory Board, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Sociology Department, Mr. Bell, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Summer Activities--Requests for Information About, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Symposium--U.S. Intervention in Latin America, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Student Loan Information, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Telegrams, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Trips--R.M. Morse, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - University Committee on Latin American Policy, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Urban Studies Committee, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 33 - 35)
  - Ventures, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Yale College--Georges May, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Yale University Press, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Universidad de Antioquia, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Publishers
    - U of F Press: From Community to Metropolis, 1955-1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Daedalus, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Holt, Rinehart & Winston Inc., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Department of Political Science, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - PRAXIS. Journal of City Government and Community Affairs, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Prospective Students, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Reprints--Morse, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Great Lakes Colleges Association, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Kansas, The University of (Lawrence), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - North Carolina, The University of (Chapel Hill), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Massachusetts University (Amherst), 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Universidad de Puerto Rico, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Princeton, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - University of Pittsburgh Department of History, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Sao Paulo, University of, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - New York University, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - State University of New York, Plattsburgh, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Stanford University. California, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Connecticut, University of, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Pan American Institute of Geography and History. Department of State, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Office of Educational Research, 1965, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 60)